Sumukh Nitundila

8762771011

<u>sumukh14@gmail.com</u> https://github.com/Boredphilosopher96 D 8/7, WMS Compound, Jayanagar 5th block, Bengaluru - 560041

Profile

A software engineer with 1 year work experience in architecting, designing and developing apps in multiple platforms from scratch. Have been responsible for starting a tech team and also being the point of contact between the business team and the tech team. My strength is in designing elegant and scalable server side code. I am also an enthusiastic learner always looking for a challenge.

Experience

ELAI (FORMERLY DEXLER AGRO) - 2019 JANUARY - 2020 MARCH

- Built a web based dashboard with microservices architecture using React JS, Redux for the front-end, Node JS, Express middleware and MongoDB for the back-end.
- Built an Android app with 500+ downloads in 2 months using Figma for design, RetroFit as a REST client and Firebase OAuth API for authentication.
- Built a machine learning model using Tensorflow to classify images with 99.6% accuracy and hosted it on a Flask server.

SIEMENS HEALTHINEERS - INTERNSHIP - JUNE 2017 - JULY 2018

- Built a C++ MFC application using the DICOMMerge library to encrypt sensitive patient data
- Built a WPF application using C# to filter through application logs
- Was involved in maintaining Syngo.Plaza tool.

LEANOVATE - INTERNSHIP - OCTOBER 2017-DECEMBER 2017

Built a python module which scrapes data from social media and performs sentiment analysis with 96% accuracy to extrapolate the pulse of the public on an issue

Education

BMS College Of Engineering – BE in Information Science(2015-2019)

Passed with distinction and a CGPA of 8.58

Skills

TECHNOLOGIES COMFORTABLE WITH:

Javascript, Java, Python, C++, Node JS, Express JS, React JS, Spring Boot, Keras, MongoDB, MySQL, Git, Android, Firebase, GCP, AWS, Apache Kafka

TECHNOLOGIES FAMILIAR WITH:

C#, WPF, MFC, Flask, Selenium, Spring Hibernate. JavaFX, Docker, Jekins

Projects

DIABETIC RETINOPATHY DETECTION

- Used OpenCV to preprocess the images and prevent overfitting
- Built a custom CNN model using Keras and did a comparison study with open source models such as Inception-V2, ResNet and VGG-16
- Used transfer learning from ResNet to increase accuracy to 93%

CHAT APPLICATION

- Built a NodeJS application to build a secure chat application which uses only session storage to record messages.
- Used Socket IO to establish a realtime bi-directional communication.